JUAN CARLOS GONZALEZ

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER



626-290-3025



jcgp1973@gmail.com



2576 Avenida del Vista Corona, CA 92882

EDUCATION

B.S. INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING Catholic University of Colombia, Bogota / Colombia 1995 - 2000

Cal OSHA 10-Hour
Construction Safety and Health
10-Hour Occupational Safety and Health Training
Course
May 2016

OSHA 30-Hour Construction Feb 2019

Certificate OSHA 7500 - Introduction to safety and Health Management California State University Dominguez Hills College of Extended and International Education Mar 2019

SKILLS

- Strong coordinating, planning and problem solving skills.
- A flexible professional who enjoys learning new skills and quickly adapts to organizational changes.
- Proficient with Microsoft Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook.
- Expertise with RF scanning hand held systems.
- Knowledge of WMS (warehouse management systems).
- Knowledge of COFE (continuous order fulfillment enterprise) that is a WCS (warehouse control system) that processes orders in the distribution center.
- Knowledge of SOP –standard operation procedure.
- Expertise in FedEx ship manager, UPS world ship software and LTL freight software.
- Bilingual in Spanish and English

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I am a motivated professional with experience in high-volume warehousing environments and safety professional on construction field. I have gained this experience through out different types of industries such as: ecommerce, multinational fashion industry, construction. Combined supervisor skills with visionary thinking to target specific needs of an organization, their employees and their customers.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Safety Inspector II

Petersen Dean Roofing and Solar, Anaheim, CA Feb 2016 – Jun 2020

- Industrial hazard identification; hazard evaluation; hazard control design; hazard control verification at the regional level (job site inspections).
- Safety / health program design; program evaluation; communication at the regional level.
- Investigation, First Incident Report (FIR), Incident Analysis Report (IAR) and statistical reporting; safety awareness and education; environmental at the regional level.
- Ensured that employees are following safety regulations (OSHA, Company Safety Policies) conducting daily on site job inspections (Job Hazard Analysis - JHA).
- Prepared Field Safety Weekly Reports (FSWR).
- Train new employees on safety regulations (OSHA and company safety policies) for roofing positions, superintendents, and drivers.
- Keeping up to date safety and training documentation.

Assistant Manager E-Commerce DC

Forever 21 INC, Los Angeles, CA Oct 2011 – Feb 2016

- Manage the Inbound area at E-Commerce, and a group of 70 employees which process all merchandise in a time of 8 hours to be in location to allow the order filling area to pick the units to fulfill the customer orders.
- Supervised problem resolution (PR) area to process the orders from customers and ensure 100 % commitment in the service.
- Provide support to production and daily activities in areas of picking, reserve stock replenish (RSR), induction (sorting of merchandise), speed pack (matching), problem resolution (PR), and packing.
- Supervised, coordinated and managed the process, activities, and verified products (clothing, accessories) being sorted, packed and shipped for store distribution at BEUMER sorter in the fulfillment area at Forever 21 INC.
- Supervised the performance, attendance of more than 30 employees at BEUMER sorter area to ensure quality in the process.

Operations Supervisor

Adesso INC, Walnut, CA Aug 2007 – Sep 2010

- Coordinated activities as receiving goods and stocked new inventory to ensure that all electronic products were shipped to the final customer within 24 hours.
- Verified physical inventory every week to comply with company guidelines and customer requirements.
- Monitored all process, including accuracy of inventory to avoid short ship orders to final customers.
- Shipped and tracked activities to ensure safe, prompt, and accurate transportation of electronic goods.